# Elisabeth Mayr

# Summary

Freelance UX Designer based in London with a background in marketing and copywriting. Experience in iOS and Android native apps, tablet and web design and working in an agile environment with developers in-house as well as remote teams.

## **Software Skills**

**UX/UI** Sketch, Figma, Photoshop, Illustrator, Balsamiq

**Prototyping** Marvel, Invision, Principle

Flow charts Visio, Lucidchart, Miro

HTML/CSS Dreamweaver, Visual Studio Code

Languages German (native), English, Thai

# Education

BA (Hons) Advertising and Brand Management

Staffordshire University • First-class honours

Advertising Academy

Market Communication

### Recommendation

"Elisabeth is a very talented designer with a real flair for ensuring that her designs are not only eye catching, but meet the needs of her clients and users alike. She works hard to ensure that she keeps up-to-date with the latest technology and techniques. She has an excellent eye for detail and great work ethic."

Karen Mackey, IT Project Manager

# Work Experience

### FREELANCE UX/UI DESIGNER | since May 2019-now

#### Monkeys Play Drums Ltd

- Improving and creating new user journeys, wireframes and high res designs for a desktop based SaaS product
- Implementing new journeys for a white label mobile app for merchants of different sizes for features required due to the Corona pandemic like the option to order and pay at table
- Redesign of a data analysis software for desktop, tablet and mobile including prototyping in Principle and user testing
- Creating personas as well as UX and UI for a native iOS and Android app for a pharmacy product
- Shaping the product goals and idea, work flows, wireframes, prototypes, information architecture and UI for a green field head hunting tool
- Participating in design workshops to come up with ideas and enhance existing journeys and designs
- Research, user flows, wireframes, information architecture and user testing for an Al powered HR tool
- Redesign of a CRM publishing tool, ensuring consistency across the platform

### **HEAD OF DESIGN** | February - May 2019

#### Jaggu

- Leading design for several web products providing consumer insights using Artificial intelligence and Machine Learning for a range of clients including Dell and Kantar
- Handover and communication with a development team in India
- Defining brand guidelines and ensuring consistency across platforms

### **DESIGN TEAM LEAD** July 2016 - February 2019

#### Apex Mobiletech

- Implementing new processes throughout the design department and across the company to improve efficiency and motivation
- Sketches, wireframes, prototypes, sitemaps and high level designs for existing software
- Design for a 3D/VR property simulation native application for web and desktop
- Creating interactive design patterns in HTML/CSS to ensure consistency across projects
- Team Management across multiple time zones
- Redesign of Apex' core tablet application
- Creating personas based on user research

### MARKETING ASSISTANT | Oct 2015 - July 2016

#### **AppyParking**

- Design and copywriting of e-mail newsletters
- Social Media posts, analytics & responses (Facebook, Twitter, Youtube, Vimeo, LinkedIn)
- Customer Lifecycle (CRM, in-app journeys, user retention)
- iOS and Android app designs
- Building the website based on a HTML/CSS template
- Prototyping and user testing
- Qualitative and quantitative user research

### JUNIOR CREATIVE | Jul.-Sept 2015 (intern) | Oct - Dec 2015 (freelancer) Steel London

E-mail design for Debenhams and TalkTalk

# COPYWRITING INTERN | Feb 2013 - May 2014 (part-time) DDB Tribal Vienna

 Copywriting for McDonald's, T-Mobile, Persil, Spar and Ottakringer